♪ ♪
- The quality of the food really dips
食物的质量在Nicky去烹饪营时真的会下降。
when Nicky goes away to cooking camp.
我不知道。
- [scoffs] I don't know.
Dicky的布朗尼看起来很不错。
Dicky's brownie looks pretty good.
那是个烤奶酪三明治。
- That's a grilled cheese.
是的，它是。
- [muffled] Yeah, it is.
别看现在，但是Nasty Nelly和她那帮War Pig就在那边。
- Don't look now, but Nasty Nelly
在哪里？
and her War Pig posse are over there.
我说了，“别看。”
- all: Where?
看她。
- I said, "Don't look."
我说了，“别看。”
Look at her. - both: Where?
看她。
- I said, "Don't look."
我说了，“别看。”
- You also said, "Look."
你也说了，“看。”
- Yeah. - You kind of did.
是的。
- I can't believe Nelly is showing her face around here
你确实说了。
after what she and her War Pigs
我真不敢相信Nelly居然敢在这里露面
did to us last year.
在她和她的战猪们
Hey, what do you think those War Pigs were doing
去年对我们做了那样的事之后。
with that big pot of spaghetti on the sidelines?
嘿，你觉得那些战猪在边线上拿着那一大锅意大利面在做什么？
- No idea.
不知道。
[squelching sound]
（咯吱声）
I was pulling pasta out of my ears for weeks.
我耳朵里掏出面条好几个星期。
[shudders] I haven't eaten spaghetti since.
（颤抖）从那以后我再也没吃过意大利面。
- War Pigs comin' our way.
战争猪朝我们来了。
- Nice café.
咖啡馆不错。
Do you serve spaghetti in...
你们提供意大利面在……
ear?
耳朵里？
[laughter]
（笑声）
- What are you doing here, Nelly?
你来这里做什么，Nelly？
- Just wanted to let you Buffaloes know:
- 只是想告诉你们这些野牛：
in case you're planning on getting
如果你们计划
a little payback for last year, don't.
为去年的事寻求报复，别费心了。
The War Pigs are watching you.
战猪们正盯着你们。
[all snorting]
[所有人哼哼]
- Let's go, Pigs.
- 走吧，猪们。
[snorting]
[哼哼]
- Wait. Payback for last year?
- 等等。去年的报复？
That's a great idea.
那是个好主意。
- You'd really get payback for me?
- 你真的会为我报复吗？
- Yeah. You mess with one Buffalo,
- 是的。你惹了一个水牛，
you mess with the whole herd.
就是惹了整个群体。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 对。- 对。
- We just have to figure out how.
- 我们只需要想出办法来。
- Hey, guys, just reminding you,
- 嘿，伙计们，提醒你们一下，
it's Mom's birthday tomorrow,
明天是妈妈的生日，
and every year we--we mess up by not getting her a gift,
每年我们都会因为没给她准备礼物而搞砸，
but not this year. Don't forget.
但今年不能这样。别忘了。
Get her something nice.
给她准备点好的礼物。
I, uh...
我，呃...
I got her this fancy but expensive locket.
我给她买了这个精美但昂贵的项链盒。
Huh? Ooh.
嗯？哦。
Ah.
啊。
Ooh, ah.
哦，啊。
She's gonna love it. So you guys on board?
她会非常喜欢的。你们都同意吗？
- Yeah. - Yeah, sure am.
- 是的。 - 当然，我同意。
- Of course, got ya. - Okay, good.
- 当然，明白。 - 好的，很好。
[box snaps shut] Ooh!
[盒子啪的一声关上] 哦！
Ah.
啊。
- I got it!
- 我拿到了！
They messed with our mascot,
他们动了我们的吉祥物，
so we'll mess with theirs.
我们就动他们的。
Let's steal their war pig.
我们去偷他们的战猪。
all: Yeah!
好！
Steal their pig! Steal their pig!
偷他们的猪！偷他们的猪！
Steal their pig!
偷他们的猪！
We stole their stinkin' War Pig!
我们偷了他们那臭烘烘的战猪！
[wild cheering]
（热烈的欢呼声）
- And he's so cute.
它真可爱。
all: Aww.
哇。
[pig farts]
[猪放屁]
all: Ew.
所有人: 哎呀。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪ ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
♪ ♪
- This is so exciting!
- 这太令人兴奋了！
I can't believe we pulled off this pignapping.
我简直不敢相信我们成功地实施了这次绑猪行动。
- This is just phase one.
- 这只是第一阶段。
- Phase two is to get him
- 第二阶段是要让他
in an Edgewood cheerleader costume
穿上Edgewood啦啦队队服
and post embarrassing pictures on FaceShack.
并把尴尬的照片上传到FaceShack。
- We'll be the heroes of the whole school.
- 我们将会成为全校的英雄。
[cell phone chimes]
[手机铃声]
Dooley's on his way over with a wig and tiny dress now.
杜利正带着假发和小裙子赶过来。
- I feel so alive!
我感觉如此充满活力！
Revenge has changed me.
复仇改变了我。
[deeper voice] I'm Bad Boy Ricky now,
我现在是坏男孩里奇了，
and I'm not afraid of anything. [car door slams outside]
我什么都不怕。
[shouting] Ah! It's Nelly and the War Pigs!
啊！是内利和战争猪！
Everybody hide!
大家快躲起来！
Move!
快动！
- Oh, no. Maybe they saw us take the pig
哦，不。也许他们看到我们带走了猪
and followed us home.
然后跟着我们回家了。
- Nobody followed us.
没人跟着我们。
[doorknob rattles]
[门把手摇晃]
- They followed us!
- 他们跟踪我们了！
- Come on, run!
- 快跑！
[all breathing heavily]
[所有人呼吸急促]
- That was close.
- 好险。
- Wait. Where's the pig?
- 等等。猪呢？
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[pig snorting and squealing]
[猪哼哼和尖叫]
- Anne? Kids? Anybody home?
- 安妮？孩子们？有人在家吗？
- That's not Nelly. That's Dad.
- 那不是内利。那是爸爸。
- Should we tell him about the pig?
我们应该告诉他关于那只猪的事吗？
- What? No one's telling Dad anything.
什么？没人会告诉爸爸任何事的。
- So we're just going to lie to him?
所以我们打算对他撒谎？
- Isn't the chance of getting payback on Nelly
为了有机会对Nelly和战争猪报复
and the War Pigs worth telling one little lie?
撒一个小谎难道不值得吗？
- Bad Boy Ricky would do it.
坏小子Ricky会这么做的。
- Yeah, he would...
是啊，他会这么做...
[deeper voice] And he'd like it.
（更深沉的声音）而且他会喜欢这么做。
I'm in.
我加入了。
Let the lying begin.
让撒谎开始吧。
- Okay, easy, Bad Boy.
- 好的，别紧张，坏小子。
We're only telling one little lie.
我们只是说一个小谎。
Oh, here. [pig snorting]
哦，这里。[猪哼哼]
We can hide the pig in here.
我们可以把猪藏在这里。
Dad will never know.
爸爸永远不会知道。
- Good idea.
- 好主意。
Things get lost in here.
东西在这里很容易丢失。
I left a burrito in a jacket over a month ago.
我一个月前在一个夹克里放了一个玉米卷。
Still haven't found it.
到现在还没找到。
- [sniffs] Ugh.
- [嗅] 呃。
Found it.
找到了。
- Hey, what are you doing in the closet?
嘿，你在衣柜里做什么？
- Uh...just hanging out.
呃...只是闲逛。
[bell dings]
叮咚
- Yeah.
是啊。
We realized we have a whole room that we never spend any time in.
我们意识到我们有一个房间，我们从来没花时间在里面。
[bell dings]
叮咚
[whispering] Okay. Two little lies.
（低语）好吧。两个小谎。
- Well, stay out of there. I got important stuff
好吧，别去那里。我在那个衣柜里放了重要的东西。现在过来。
in that closet. Now come on.
帮我给你妈妈准备这个生日蛋糕。
Help me set up this cake for your mom's birthday.
帮我一起给你妈妈准备生日蛋糕。
- Ooh, Mom's birthday. When is it?
哦，妈妈的生日。什么时候？
- Today.
今天。
- It is? - It is?
是吗？
- What--were you even listening to me
when I told you yesterday?
什么——你昨天有在听我说话吗？
Hey, kids. Just reminding ya.
嘿，孩子们。只是提醒一下。
Blah, blah, blah. Dad stuff.
blah blah blah。爸爸的事。
Dad stuff, shiny thing. Blah...
爸爸的事，闪亮的东西。blah...
- Of course we were listening to you.
当然我们在听你说话。
[bell dings]
- Good, 'cause your mother deserves
好，因为你们的妈妈值得
a great birthday present.
一个很棒的生日礼物。
- Which we definitely got her.
我们当然已经给她准备好了。
[bell dings]
- [gasps]
all: Happy Birthday!
大家：生日快乐！
- Aw, you remembered.
哦，你们还记得。
- Of course we did.
当然记得。
- We also remembered
我们也记得
your favorite birthday tradition:
你的最爱的生日传统：
cake for breakfast.
早餐吃蛋糕。
- Oh, Tom. You shouldn't have.
- 哦，汤姆。你真不该这样。
- Well. - [laughing]
- 嗯。 - [笑]
Hmm.
嗯。
"Happy Birthday for Tom?"
“汤姆的生日快乐？”
- What? What?
- 什么？什么？
No!
不！
I said it was supposed to say "Happy Birthday,"
我说应该是“生日快乐”，
and the order was for Tom.
而且订单是给汤姆的。
Not "for Tom." For Tom!
不是“给Tom”。是给Tom的！
- It's okay. It's still cake for breakfast.
没关系。早餐吃蛋糕也不错。
- No, no, no, no! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
不，不，不，不！等等，等等，等等，等等。
No, no, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不，不。
You deserve better.
你应该得到更好的。
Oh. - No.
哦。不。
- Which is why we all got you amazing gifts.
这就是为什么我们都给你准备了很棒的礼物。
I'm gonna get mine...
我去拿我的……
mmm, out of the closet.
嗯，从衣柜里拿出来。
[kids exclaiming]
[孩子们惊呼]
- Tom, I really wanted that cake.
- 汤姆，我真的很想要那块蛋糕。
- [exclaims] Pig! Pig in the house!
- [惊呼] 猪！家里有猪！
- Tom!
- 汤姆！
- No, no. Real pig in the house!
- 不，不。真的有猪在家里！
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
[pig snorting and squealing]
[猪哼哼和尖叫]
Who brought this pig into my house?
谁把这头猪带到我家里来的？
- Well, it definitely wasn't me.
- 呃，肯定不是我。
- Because I love pigs!
- 因为我喜欢猪！
- Well, that's why we got one for you.
- 嗯，这就是我们为什么给你弄了一头猪。
[bell dings]
铃声响起
- kids: Happy birthday, Mom!
- 孩子们：妈妈，生日快乐！
♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Guys, what a thoughtful present.
- 伙计们，真是贴心的礼物。
Did you get me a pig because you knew I had one
你们送我一头猪，是因为知道我小时候在农场长大时养过一头吗？
as a little girl growing up on the farm?
- 呃...是的。
- Uh...yeah.
铃声再次响起
[bell dings]
对吧，伙计们？
Right, guys?
- 呃，是的。确实是这样。- 完全正确。- 梅也帮了忙。
- Uh, yes. That is true.
- 嗯，是的，没错。
- Totally. - Mae helped too.
- 完全正确。- 梅也帮了忙。
- Why'd you bring me into it?
- 你为什么把我扯进来？
- Sorry, if Bad Boy Ricky goes down,
- 抱歉，如果坏小子里基倒下，
he's taking everybody with him.
- 他会拖所有人下水。
- Well... [sighs]
- 嗯...[叹气]
I got you a thoughtful gift too, Anne.
- 我也给你准备了一个贴心的礼物，安妮。
But it looks like our porky friend
- 但看起来我们的猪朋友
made a meal out of it in the closet.
- 在衣柜里把它当饭吃了。
[snorting]
- [哼哼声]
[knocking at door]
[敲门声]
- Hey, guys. all: Hey, Dooley.
- 嘿，伙计们。大家: 嘿，杜利。
- Happy birthday, Mrs. H.
- 生日快乐，H太太。
- Well, thank you, Dooley.
- 嗯，谢谢你，杜利。
- Yeah. Thanks, Dooley.
- 是的。谢谢，杜利。
- Now down to business.
- 现在谈正事。
You got someplace we can talk?
你们有地方可以谈谈吗？
- Yeah. Have you seen our closet?
- 是的。你们见过我们的衣橱吗？
[laughs nervously]
[紧张地笑]
[whispering] Closet.
[低声说] 衣橱。
- They hang out in there now.
- 他们现在就待在那里面。
[pig snorting]
[猪哼声]
- I don't like to toot my own horn,
- 我不喜欢自吹自擂，
but this is a Dooley doozy.
但这次是个杜利的大难题。
So...toot.
所以...吹吧。
One pig-sized cheerleader outfit as requested.
按照要求，准备了一套适合猪尺寸的拉拉队服装。
Go, Buffaloes!
加油，野牛队！
- Look, Dooley, there's been a tiny complication.
- 听着，杜利，出了点小问题。
Turns out-- - Bup-bup-bup.
结果是—— - 等等。
I only need to know what I need to know.
我只需要知道我需要知道的。
- [laughs] Bad Boy Ricky gets it.
- [笑]坏男孩瑞奇明白了。
This way, you're off the hook if the law gets wise.
这样，如果法律变得明智，你就脱身了。
Nice.
不错。
- He's calling himself "Bad Boy Ricky" now?
- 他现在自称“坏男孩瑞奇”？
- Yes, he is.
- 是的，他是。
- Dooley's gonna be honest with you.
- 杜利会对你说实话。
It's a tough sell.
这很难卖出去。
[closet door opens, closes]
[衣橱门打开，关闭]
- What are we going to do?
- 我们该怎么办？
- If we still want to be the school heroes,
- 如果我们还想成为学校的英雄，
we're gonna have to get that pig away from Mom
我们要把那只猪从妈妈那里弄走
so we can finish our revenge.
这样我们才能完成我们的复仇计划。
- But how?
- 但是怎么做呢？
[dog barking]
[狗叫声]
- Squishy!
- 斯奎西！
We'll convince Mom this house isn't big enough
我们要说服妈妈这个房子不够大
for Squishy and the pig.
不适合斯奎西和那只猪。
- Dooley, this is lovely.
- 杜利，这太好了。
How did you find a picture of my grandmother?
你怎么找到我祖母的照片的？
- Bup-bup-bup.
- 等等。
- I got her a necklace first.
- 我先给她买了一条项链。
- That's a good, good boy. [dog growling]
- 真是个好孩子。[狗在低吼]
- Oh, no, Mom, it looks like Squishy
- 哦，不，妈妈，看起来Squishy
doesn't like the pig.
不喜欢这只猪。
- I hate to say it, but we might have to give the pig back.
- 我真不想这么说，但我们可能得把猪还回去。
[dog barking] - Squishy agrees.
[狗在叫] - Squishy也同意。
- No, back on the farm, it always took a while
- 不，在农场，猪和狗总是需要一段时间
for a pig to warm up to a pup.
才能互相熟悉起来。
They'll love each other by the time
到我们拍全家福的时候，
we take the family portrait.
它们会彼此相爱的。
- Whose family portrait?
- 谁的家族肖像？
- Ours. Don't you remember?
- 我们的。你不记得了吗？
It's my birthday gift to myself.
这是我送给自己的生日礼物。
We're taking it this afternoon
我们今天下午拍
when Nicky gets back from camp.
等尼基从营地回来的时候。
I told you about it yesterday.
我昨天告诉过你的。
[kids chanting "Steal their pig!"]
[孩子们高喊“偷他们的猪！”]
- Honey, do me a favor.
- 亲爱的，帮我个忙。
Blah, blah. Wife stuff, wife stuff.
blah, blah. 妻子的事，妻子的事。
Blah, blah, blah. Don't forget.
blah, blah, blah. 别忘了。
You totally forgot.
你完全忘记了。
- No, I didn't.
不，我没有。
[bell dings]
叮咚。
- Okay, well, since you remembered, you also remember
好吧，既然你记得，你也记得
that we'll all be wearing crisp,
我们都会穿着整洁的白色亚麻衬衫拍照。
white linen shirts for the portrait.
哦，你能顺便给小猪也买一件吗？
Oh, can you pick up a little one for the piggy, too?
我到底该去哪儿找
- Where the heck am I supposed to find
一件整洁的白色亚麻衬衫给猪穿？
a crisp, white linen shirt for a pig?
嘘。
- Psst. - [exclaims]
哎呀。
- Go to this address. Knock on the back door.
- 去这个地址。敲后门。
[whispering] Ask for Doug.
[低语] 找道格。
[pig snorting] - Oh, you're so cute.
[猪哼哼] - 哦，你真可爱。
I'm gonna call you...
我要叫你...
[gasps] Tooty Snoots!
[吸气] 图蒂·斯努茨！
- Okay, fine. You know I'm a sucker
- 好吧，好吧。你知道我对你起的昵称没抵抗力。
when you give me nicknames.
图蒂·斯努茨。
Tooty Snoots.
- 来吧，图蒂·斯努茨。
- You come on, Tooty Snoots.
- 等等。你要去哪儿？
- Wait. Where are you going?
- 你不能带着猪离开。
- You can't leave with the pig.
- Well, how else am I supposed to give Tooty a bath
before his portrait?
- We're never going to get that pig away from her.
- Maybe we should just let her keep it.
- You mean actually steal the pig
from Nelly and the War Pigs?
[deeper voice] B.B.R. likes it.
Bad Boy Ricky likes to abbreviate.
- It's probably better for the pig anyway.
There's no way Nelly and those War Pigs
无论如何，Nelly和那些战争猪
could love it as much as your mom does.
都不可能像你妈妈那样爱它。
- I loved that pig
- 我比任何人都更爱那只猪
more than anyone could ever love anything.
超过任何人能爱任何事物。
- So I was wrong.
- 所以我错了。
- And if I find out someone took him,
- 如果我发现有人带走了他，
they're gonna pay.
他们将会付出代价。
The team and I are going all around the neighborhood
我和我的团队正在整个社区四处张贴这些传单，试图找到他。
with these flyers, trying to find him.
他的名字叫Pigsley Coleman。他是以我们的教练命名的。
His name is Pigsley Coleman. He's named after our coach.
你的教练名字是Pigsley？
- Your coach's name is Pigsley?
- 你们教练的名字是Pigsley吗？
- No, Coleman.
- 不是，是Coleman。
You have to let me know if you see him.
如果你看到他，一定要告诉我。
- Who? Your coach?
- 谁？你的教练吗？
- No, the pig.
- 不是，是那只猪。
- But you're also looking
- 但你也在找
for your coach? - No.
你的教练吗？ - 不是。
- Then why'd you put his face on the flyer?
- 那你为什么把他的脸放在传单上？
- That's a pig.
- 那是一只猪。
- Huh. All right.
- 嗯。好吧。
- So have you seen him or not?
- 那你到底见没见过他？
all: No.
没有。
[bell dinging]
[铃声叮当]
- But there is a great big world out there.
- 但外面有一个广阔的世界。
I mean, he could be anywhere but here.
我是说，他可能在哪里，但不是这里。
- He could be anywhere.
- 他可能在任何地方。
I'm never gonna find him.
我永远找不到他。
He may be the team's mascot,
他可能是队伍的吉祥物，
but I was the one who raised him
但我是从小把他养大的那个人。
since he was a little baby pig.
自从他还是个小猪宝宝的时候。
Oh, Pigsley! Pigsley!
哦，皮格斯利！皮格斯利！
- Wow, she really loved that pig.
哇，她真的很爱那只猪。
- Or her coach.
或者是她的教练。
- Could you please excuse us a second?
请问你们能稍等一下吗？
- All right, now we have two people
好了，现在我们有两个人
who love the same pig. What do we do?
都爱同一只猪。我们该怎么办？
- Tell everybody the truth and accept the consequences.
告诉大家真相并接受后果。
- [laughing]
[笑]
[deeper voice] Here's how it's going down.
[更深沉的声音]事情会这样发展。
We get Dooley to score us an identical pig,
我们让杜利为我们找一只一模一样的猪，
do the old switcheroo with Pigsley,
用Pigsley的老把戏调换一下，
then sneak him back to his digs,
然后悄悄把他送回他的窝，
and no one's the wiser.
这样就没人会察觉。
Capisce?
明白吗？
- Who are you?
- 你是谁？
- I'm B.B.R., dang it.
- 我是B.B.R.，该死。
- You know that's Mom's hat, right?
- 你知道那是妈妈的帽子，对吧？
- B.B.R. don't care.
- B.B.R.不在乎。
- All right.
- 好吧。
I'll text Dooley.
我会给Dooley发短信。
- Nelly, we're really sorry about Pigsley,
内莉，我们真的很抱歉关于皮格斯利，
but I wouldn't worry.
但我不担心。
I'm sure he'll show up before you know it.
我肯定他很快就会出现。
[pig squeals]
[猪叫声]
- [whispering] Or he'll show up now.
（低语）或者他现在就会出现。
- [whispering] We got Mom.
（低语）我们找到妈妈了。
You guys take Nelly.
你们带内莉走。
- So, Nelly.
那么，内莉。
Tell us more about this "Pigsley" of yours.
跟我们多说说你的“皮格斯利”吧。
- Okay, Tooty Snoots.
好的，图蒂·斯努茨。
- Hey, Mom. Where are you going?
嘿，妈妈。你要去哪儿？
- Oh, I'm just taking Tooty upstairs
哦，我只是带图蒂上楼
to dry him off after his bath.
给他洗完澡后把他弄干。
- No, you can't!
不行，你不能去！
- What? Why not?
什么？为什么不能？
- Because we really want you to tell us about life on the farm.
因为我们真的很想让你给我们讲讲农场的生活。
[bell dings]
[铃声响了]
Bet you had a lot of good stories
我敢打赌，你有很多关于羊的好故事，对吧？
about sheep, huh?
不，我们没有羊。
- No, we didn't have any sheep.
那鸡呢？- 没有。
- What about chickens? - Nope.
- 那鸡呢？ - 没有。
- Cows? - No.
- 牛呢？ - 没有。
- A funny donkey?
- 一只滑稽的驴子？
- [laughs nervously]
- [紧张地笑]
[pig squealing]
[猪叫声]
- Is that oinking?
- 那是猪叫声吗？
- Uh, no, that's not oinking. That's...
- 呃，不是，那不是猪叫声。那是...
- Dawn.
- 道恩。
- Yeah, she has really bad allergies.
- 是的，她过敏很严重。
[bell dings]
[铃声]
In fact, we all do,
事实上，我们都有，
right, Dicky?
对吧，Dicky？
[bell dings]
[coughing and hacking]
[咳嗽和干咳]
[both coughing]
[两人都在咳嗽]
[pig squealing]
[猪叫声]
- That sounds just like Pigsley.
那听起来就像Pigsley。
[crying] I miss him so much!
[哭泣]我好想他！
[sobbing]
[啜泣]
- Who's crying in the living room?
谁在客厅里哭？
- It's...
是...
Dad!
爸爸！
[bell dings]
Yeah, he is all broken up
是的，他因为整个生日礼物的事情非常伤心。
about the whole birthday gift thing.
哦，是啊，我应该去看看他。
- Aww. Yeah, I should go check on him.
等等，妈妈！
- Wait, Mom!
不！
No!
哦。
Oh.
（低声）他们在哪儿？
[whispering] Where are they?
（低声）我不知道。
- [whispering] I don't know.
- [whispering] 我不知道。
- I just tried to get you another cake, Anne.
- 我刚刚试着再给你拿个蛋糕，安妮。
- Aw. - Mm-hmm.
- 啊。 - 嗯哼。
- "Happy Birthday, Dan." Hmm.
- “生日快乐，丹。”嗯。
Who's Dan?
谁是丹？
- You are, Anne.
- 你是，安妮。
You're Dan.
你是丹。
I'd like to say it's short for "Darling Anne,"
我倒是想说这是“亲爱的安妮”的简称，
but it isn't.
但不是。
I swear that Schneider's Bakery wants me to fail.
我发誓施耐德面包店想让我失败。
- Honey, it's okay.
亲爱的，没关系。
As long as you got this little guy a shirt
只要你给这个小家伙准备了一件衬衫
for the family portrait,
拍全家福时穿，
I'm gonna have a happy birthday.
我就会有一个快乐的生日。
- I'll be right back, Dan.
我马上回来，丹。
- Oh, hey, get lunch for the kids.
哦，对了，给孩子们买点午餐。
I won't have time to make lunch
摄影师来之前我没时间做午饭。
before the photographer gets here.
你和你兄弟们也需要准备一下。
And you and your brothers need to get ready.
好的！
- Will do!
我一找到他们就办。
As soon as I find out where the heck they are.
一旦我知道他们到底在哪里。
[phone chimes]
[手机提示音]
- Oh, Dicky just texted us.
- 哦，Dicky刚刚给我们发了短信。
They took Nelly out to "pretend to look for harp egg."
他们带Nelly出去“假装找竖琴蛋”。
Wait, I think that's supposed to say "look for her pig."
等等，我想那应该是说“找她的猪”。
- Ugh. Dicky never checks his autocorrect.
- 唉。Dicky从来不检查他的自动更正。
[phone chimes]
[手机提示音]
- I guess that's why he just texted
- 我想这就是为什么他刚刚发短信说
that he and Ricky "will be bite rack
他和Ricky“会在薄荷新特里咬架”。
in a mint newt."
在一块全新的新特里。
♪ ♪
- Where are they?
她们在哪儿呢？
Finally.
终于。
Okay, how'd it go with Nelly?
好，跟内莉谈得怎么样了？
- Perfect. She's totally off our trail.
完美。她完全没发现我们的行踪。
- And Nelly's actually pretty cool.
而且内莉其实挺酷的。我们现在已经是脸书好友了。
We're FaceShack friends now. - You are?
真的吗？
- Yeah, we have a lot in common.
对，我们有很多共同点。
She lost her pig.
她丢了一头猪。
I stole her pig.
我偷了她的猪。
I guess that's it.
我想就是这样了。
[phone chimes]
[手机提示音]
Dooley's almost here. - Great.
杜利快到了。 - 太好了。
As soon as Mom comes down,
妈妈一下来，
we get the pig from her, make the switcheroo,
我们就从她那里拿到猪，进行调换，
and we're back on track for payback.
然后我们就可以继续进行报复计划了。
Here. - Okay.
给。 - 好的。
You kids ready for the picture?
你们准备好拍照了吗？
- Absolutely. - Great.
- 当然。 - 太好了。
- Oh, and I love that new hair clip.
- 哦，我喜欢你那个新发夹。
- What new hair clip?
- 什么新发夹？
- Oh, the one that's moving in your hair.
- 哦，那个在你头发里动的发夹。
- What? - Okay, bug in you hair!
- 什么？ - 好吧，头发里有虫子！
Bug in your hair! - Oh, get it out!
头发里有虫子！ - 哦，快把它弄出来！
Come on! Come on, help!
快点！快点，帮忙！
Help! Get it out!
帮忙！把它弄出来！
Did you get it?
你弄出来了吗？
- I think I did. Got it!
- 我想我弄出来了。弄出来了！
[bell dings]
[铃声叮当]
- [exhales]
- [叹气]
- But ya...
但是...
might want to run a brush through that.
可能需要用梳子梳理一下。
- Right. Thank you. Okay.
对，谢谢你。好的。
- We'll watch Tooty Snoots for you.
我们会帮你照顾Tooty Snoots。
- Oh, okay. Here you go.
哦，好的。给你。
[pig squealing]
（猪叫声）
- Okay.
好的。
Finally we can end this mess.
终于我们可以结束这场混乱了。
- I've said it before, and I'll say it again.
我之前说过，我还会再说一遍。
Toot.
Toot。
- What did you do?
你做了什么？
- Dooley brought what Dicky texted.
杜利带来了迪基发的短信内容。
- I texted "We need to get Mom an identical pig."
我发的短信是“我们需要给妈妈买一只一模一样的猪。”
- No, you texted,
不，你发的是，
"We need to get a monkey that dances a jig."
“我们需要买一只会跳吉格舞的猴子。”
- Oops.
哎呀。
- But as long as he's here...
但既然他已经在这儿了...
- Hit it, Bobo!
开始吧，波波！
[folk dancing music]
[民间舞蹈音乐]
♪ ♪
- What?
- 怎么了？
Dicky see, Dicky do.
迪基看到，迪基做。
♪ ♪
[folk dancing music]
[民间舞蹈音乐]
♪ ♪
- What are we going to do now?
- 我们现在该怎么办？
Mom is definitely going to notice
如果我们试图用猴子换掉猪，妈妈肯定会注意到的。
if we try to switch the pig with a monkey.
B.B.R.开始慌了！
B.B.R. is starting to panic!
- 杜利，我们需要一头猪。
- Dooley, we need a pig.
【哼声】我的养猪人要到周四才回来。
- [groans]
- [呻吟声]
My pig guy's out of town until Thursday.
我的养猪人周四前都不在城里。
But let me tell you what I'm gonna do for you.
但让我告诉你我能为你做什么。
The monkey?
那只猴子？
Yours.
你的了。
- Dooley, we can't-- - Bup-bup-bup-bup.
- Dooley,我们不能-- - 不不不不。
- What are we supposed to do with this monkey?
- 我们该拿这只猴子怎么办？
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- That's the photographer. Let her in!
- 那是摄影师。让她进来！
- [whispering] Closet. Come on.
- [低语] 衣橱。快点。
- All right, come on. - Come here.
- 好了，过来。 - 来这里。
- Come on.
- 来吧。
If you get hungry, there's a burrito in the gray jacket.
如果你饿了，灰色夹克里有玉米卷饼。
I hope she's not color-blind.
希望她不是色盲。
- Okay, all better.
- 好了，好多了。
Hey, where's my little piggy?
嘿，我的小猪猪呢？
- [stammering]
- [结巴]
He went to market?
他去市场了？
[all laughing nervously]
[大家都紧张地笑]
- Kids, I have something for you in the kitchen!
- 孩子们，我在厨房给你们准备了东西！
- Maybe Dad has him. - Yeah.
- 也许爸爸带他去了。 - 是啊。
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响了]
- Well, I'm sure the pig's in good hands.
- 嗯，我肯定小猪在好人家。
- Hey, check it out.
- 嘿，看看这个。
I took care of our little pig problem...
我解决了我们的小猪问题...
and I got us a delicious meal at the same time.
同时还为我们准备了一顿美味的饭菜。
- Is that a b-b-b-baby back?
- 那是bbbb婴儿肋排吗？
- Mmm. Oh, yeah.
- 嗯。哦，是的。
These are the freshest ribs I've ever had.
这是我吃过最新鲜的肋排。
Right, Squish?
对吧，Squish？
- Is that a curly pig tail?
那是卷曲的猪尾巴吗？
- Okay, guys, get in here!
好了，大家进来吧！
Nicky's home and the photographer's ready.
尼基回来了，摄影师也准备好了。
- Coming!
来了！
Boy, that little porker
那小猪崽子
was finger-lickin' good.
真是美味到让人吮指。
[laughs, snorts]
（笑，哼声）
Nicky!
尼基！
- Dad and Squishy ate the pig!
爸爸和斯奎西吃了那只猪！
- I knew they hated it,
我就知道他们不喜欢，
but that seems extreme.
但这似乎太极端了。
- Leave it!
别管了！
- Let's go, kids. The photographer's on the clock.
孩子们，我们走吧。摄影师已经在计时了。
- Nicky, how was cooking camp? - Nicholas.
尼基，烹饪营怎么样？
- Hey, Nicky. - It was good.
尼古拉斯。
- You will not believe what has gone on since you've been gone.
嘿，尼基。
- Hey, guys, where is Tooty Snoots?
挺好的。
- You're looking at him.
你不会相信你不在的时候发生了什么事。
- Why is she calling Dad "Tooty Snoots"?
嘿，伙计们，图蒂·斯努茨在哪里？
- He's not Tooty Snoots.
你正看着他呢。
- The pig was Tooty Snoots.
- 那头猪就是Tooty Snoots。
- We took him. - And tried to hide him.
- 我们把他带走了。 - 还试图藏起他。
- But Dad turned him into barbecue.
- 但爸爸把他变成了烧烤。
- Wow. Is there any left?
- 哇。还有剩下的吗？
'Cause I haven't eaten since this morning.
'因为从早上到现在我还没吃东西。
I mean...
我是说...
how horrible.
多么可怕。
- Give us our pig back!
- 把我们的猪还给我们！
- Who are you?
- 你们是谁？
- We're the War Pigs, and Pigsley is ours.
- 我们是战争猪，Pigsley是我们的。
We know you took him.
Here's the proof: a selfie Dicky posted
this morning on FaceShack.
- #pignapping.
- Dicky, why would you post that picture?
- Dude, if your hair looked that good, you'd post it too.
- Sorry, guys, I've only got five minutes to do this,
so we have to get going. - Okay, come on.
Come on, come on, come on. - Five minutes?
- I had a coupon. - Wait!
What are you doing? What about our pig?
你在干什么？我们的猪呢？
- Big smiles.
- 大笑。
- Can anyone tell me why this angry girl
- 谁能告诉我为什么这个生气的女孩
keeps calling my pig hers?
一直说我的猪是她的？
- It doesn't matter anyway, because Dad ate the pig! - What? - What?
- 反正没关系，因为爸爸吃了那只猪！ - 什么？ - 什么？
- I didn't eat the pig!
- 我没吃那只猪！
- But you said you took care of the pig problem.
- 但你说过你解决了猪的问题。
- What? Oh. Oh, no.
- 什么？哦。哦，不。
I got those baby backs from Doug's Ribs,
我从Doug的Ribs, Rubs和Tiny Shirts那里买了那些小排骨，
Rubs, and Tiny Shirts.
拿了猪的衬衫后我还去吃了点午饭。
And then I--I grabbed some--
然后我——我拿了些——
some lunch after I picked up the pig's shirt.
在拿了猪的衬衫后，我顺便吃了午餐。
- But Squishy had the pig's tail in his mouth.
- 但Squishy嘴里叼着猪的尾巴。
- Well, that was just a curly fry.
- 那只是个卷曲的薯条。
- So if he didn't eat him, where's our pig?
- 既然他没吃掉它，那我们的猪在哪里？
- Okay, why does she keep saying it's theirs?
- 好吧，她为什么一直说那是他们的？
- Because it kind of maybe just a little is theirs?
- 因为可能有点，只是有点是他们的？
- What? - Keep smiling.
- 什么？ - 保持微笑。
- We're sorry, Mom. We just wanted revenge.
- 对不起，妈妈。我们只是想报复。
- On Nelly and her team
- 对Nelly和她的团队
for filling my buffalo head with spaghetti.
为了把我的水牛头塞满意大利面。
- So anyway, the truth is...
总之，事实是...
[tape fast-forwarding, counter clicking]
[bell dings]
And now that you're all caught up
现在你们都跟上进度了
on how we got here...
关于我们是如何走到这一步的...
we're really sorry.
我们真的很抱歉。
We didn't mean for any of this to happen.
我们并不想让这一切发生。
- We just started lying, and we couldn't stop.
我们只是开始撒谎，然后就停不下来了。
- Bad Boy Ricky was feelin' it!
坏小子Ricky感觉到了！
- Who?
- 谁？
- But it's over. No more lies.
- 但一切都结束了。不再有谎言。
- Well, I appreciate you kids finally telling the truth,
- 好吧，我很感激你们这些孩子终于说出了真相，
but where is this poor girl's pig?
但是那可怜女孩的猪在哪里？
- all: Uh...
- 大家：呃...
[pig shrieking]
[猪尖叫]
- Pigsley!
- 皮格斯利！
Come here, Pigsley.
过来，皮格斯利。
[pig squealing]
[猪叫]
Come here.
过来。
- See? Everything worked out fine.
- 看吧？一切都很顺利。
So we're even, right?
- 所以我们扯平了，对吧？
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
We'll settle this on the soccer field.
- 我们将在足球场上解决这个问题。
Let's go, War Pigs.
- 走吧，战猪队。
[snorting]
[哼哼声]
[door slams]
[门砰的一声关上]
- So you forgot my birthday,
- 所以你忘了我的生日，
and you didn't get me a present.
- 而且你没给我准备礼物。
- No. - We...
- 没有。- 我们...
- Uh...
呃...
- Got you a monkey!
给你买了只猴子！
[bell dings]
叮咚
- And not just any monkey.
而且不是普通的猴子。
Hit it, Bobo.
敲它，波波。
- No, no. Don't hit it, Bobo.
不，不。别敲它，波波。
That's my locket. Now give it back.
那是我的项链。现在还给我。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[camera shutter clicks]
咔嚓
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪